gamepedia
help

sign in
register

navigation
search
(full list)
added a new hero:
.

rubick

rubick
buffed most heroes.
added.
rip tide

rip tide
added.
whirling axes

whirling axes
reworked.
overcharge

overcharge
reworked.
infest

infest
reworked
anchor smash

anchor smash
reworked.
charge of darkness

charge of darkness
reworked.
song of the siren

song of the siren
reworked's abilities.
terrorblade

terrorblade
reworked's abilities.
treant protector

treant protector
reworked's abilities.
underlord

underlord
added:
aghanim's scepter

aghanim's scepter

beastmaster

beastmaster

dark seer

dark seer

gyrocopter

gyrocopter

meepo

meepo
added a new item:

veil of discord

veil of discord
balanced items.
dota:
2011-04-27
archive
← version 6.71b
version 6.72b →
contents

1heroes
1
heroes

1.1new
1.1
new

1.2balance changes
1.2
balance changes

2items
2
items

3others
3
others

4bugs
4
bugs

5see also
5
see also
heroes
new

name:rubick, the grand magus
name:
type:intelligence
type:
alliance:sentinel
alliance:
strength:19 + 1.5
strength:
intelligence:27 + 2.4
intelligence:
agility:14 + 1.6
agility:
movement speed:300
movement speed:
attack range:600
attack range:
total starting damage:44-54
total starting damage:
total starting armor:1
total starting armor:
telekinesis
telekinesis:

lift duration: 1.5/1.75/2/2.25 seconds
stun duration: 1/1.25/1.5/1.75 (in the area it lands in, all enemy units except the initial target)
land stun aoe: 325
cast range: 550/575/600/625
cooldown: 18
mana cost: 160
while the target is in the air, rubick may use a secondary ability to control the throw the enemy in a targeted direction. maximum of 375 units away.
note: the directional landing happens when the lift duration is over, but you can issue the direction order anytime.
fade bolt
fade bolt:

damage: 75/150/225/300
attack reduction: -14/20/26/32 damage [-7/10/13/16 on creeps]
duration: 10 seconds
cast range: 800
cooldown: 10
mana cost: 90/95/100/105
null field
null field:

magic damage reduction: 5/10/15/20%
aoe: 900
spell steal
spell steal:

spell is stolen for: 3/4/5 minutes
cast range: 1000
mana cost: 25
cooldown: 20/18/16
note: if you steal another spell, the old one is lost. both teams see what spell was stolen. items cannot be stolen, only abilities. you will get a warning message when the spell steal duration is close to expiring.
note 2: there are a small set of spell exceptions (for technical reasons) that cannot be copied.
balance changes

abaddon
aphotic shield cast range increased from 350 to 450

ancient apparition
armor reduced from 4 to 2

anti-mage
base attack time improved from 1.45 to 1.35
the hero's attack rate improves the lower the base attack time is, this is a buff.

axe
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 1
battle hunger rescaled from 15/17/25/33 to 15/21/27/33 damage per second

bane
brain sap cooldown decreased from 16 to 14
fiend's grip now gives vision of the target
enfeeble now reduces attack damage by a constant amount
old:
reduces attack damage by 40/60/80/100% of base damage
mana cost: 125
cooldown: 15
new:
reduces attack damage by 25/50/75/100
mana cost: 125
cooldown: 12
note: previous was base damage only (it did not reduce bonus damage from items), this reduces total damage by a constant amount.

batrider
armor reduced by 1

beastmaster
greater hawk's invisibility fade time decreased from 8 to 5 seconds
wild axes now move at similar speed to the max range (so it isn't as slow for short range targeting)
added aghanim's scepter upgrade:

increases cast range from 600 to 950
decreases cooldown from 80/75/70 to 45

bloodseeker
bloodbath assist aoe increased from 200 to 225

bounty hunter
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
jinada cooldown decreased from 15/12/9/6 to 12/10/8/6

brewmaster
drunken haze duration increased from 7 to 8 seconds
primal split earth panda now carries the hero's auras around him
if you are carrying radiance or assault cuirass, for example, the area around your panda is affected.

bristleback
warpath damage per stack increased from 4/8/12 to 10/15/20

centaur warrunner
movement speed increased from 300 to 305
double edge cooldown decreased from 12 to 10
hoof stomp cooldown decreased from 15 to 13

chaos knight
base strength increased by 3
chaos bolt damage improved from 1*200 to 1*200/50*225/75*250/100*275
chaos bolt now has a floating text indicator for the damage done

chen
test of faith's secondary ability to teleport units is now a part of holy persuasion instead (377809)

clockwerk
armor reduced by 1

crystal maiden
freezing field level 1 mana cost decreased from 300 to 200

dark seer
wall of replica illusion damage improved from 70% to 70/80/90%
added an aghanim's scepter upgrade (and visual effect):
creates illusions of allied heroes as well as enemy heroes. allied illusions deal 50% damage.

dazzle
poison touch damage increased from 7/14/21/28 to 8/16/24/32

death prophet
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
exorcism rebalanced from 5/10/16 to 4/10/18 spirits (from 9/16/23 to 10/16/24 with witchcraft)
witchcraft bonuses rescaled to be more straightforward
old:
increases movement speed by 3/6/9/12%
decreases carrion swarm's mana cost by 5 / 10 / 15 / 20 and cooldown by 1 / 2 / 3 / 4 seconds.
decreases silence's mana cost by 0 / 10 / 20 / 30 and cooldown by 1 / 2 / 3 / 4 seconds.
increases the number of level 1 exorcism spirits by 1 / 2 / 3 / 4.
increases the number of level 2 exorcism spirits by 1 / 3 / 4 / 6.
increases the number of level 3 exorcism spirits by 0 / 2 / 4 / 7.
new:
increases movement speed by 3/6/9/12%
decreases carrion swarm and silence cooldown by 1/2/3/4 seconds
decreases carrion swarm and silence mana cost by 10/15/20/25
creates 3/4/5/6 extra spirits

doom
doom's duration decreased from 14 to 13 seconds (aghanim's doom is still 14)

dragon knight
breathe fire damage rescaled from 75/150/225/300 to 90/170/240/300

drow ranger
previous sight range nerf reverted (from 6.68)

earthshaker
echo slam initial damage reduced from 165/230/285 to 160/210/270

elder titan
ancestral spirit now has a secondary ability that returns the spirit
ancestral spirit cooldown decreased from 19 to 16
ancestral spirit cast range increased from 1000 to 1200

enchantress
aghanim's impetus range bonus increased from +150 extra to +165

faceless void
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
aghanim's upgraded chronosphere cooldown decreased from 75 to 60
chronosphere now reveals invisible units
chronosphere cast range improved from 500/550/600 to 600
time walk slow affects all units along his path, instead of just at the destination

io
base damage increased from 33*42 to 43*52
attack range increased from 525 to 575
tether movement speed bonus reduced from 15/20/25/30% to 20%
tether stun duration rebalanced from 1/1.25/1.5/1.75 to 0.75/1.25/1.75/2.25
spirits oscillation subabilities no longer interrupt wisp's movement
spirits now circle slightly faster when there are fewer alive
spirits no longer slow
spirits life duration increased by 3 seconds
spirits now spawn over 4 second interval instead of 6
overcharge reworked:
old:
grants bonus attack speed, drains 2.5% of his current hp and mp per second. if io is tethered to an ally the bonus attack speed is also granted to that ally.
this is a toggle ability.
attack speed: 60/80/100/120
new:
grants bonus attack speed and damage reduction, drains 2.5% of his current hp and mp per second. if io is tethered to an ally attack speed and damage reduction is also granted to that ally.
this is a toggle ability.
attack speed: 40/50/60/70
damage reduction: 5/10/15/20% [reduces damage taken]

gyrocopter
agility growth increased from 2.4 to 2.8
rocket barrage cooldown rescaled from 6.5 to 7/6.5/6/5.5 seconds
added an aghanim's scepter upgrade (and visual effect)
call down now has a global cast range and the second rocket does 75 more damage.

huskar
burning spears minimum hp requirement removed (it is still non*lethal)
life break cast mechanism changed:
it now has a 600 cast range and causes huskar to quickly dash forward towards the target. you are magic immune while running forward. if you get interrupted, the dash stops.

invoker
no longer gets interrupted by casting orbs or invokes
base damage reduced by 5
alacrity can now target mechanical units (1680)
alacrity mana cost increased from 50 to 100
alacrity bonus damage & attack speed decreased from 30*>90 to 20*>80
cold snap now requires a minimum of 10 damage before it triggers
ice wall no longer affects magic immune units
the invoke combinations are now displayed in the ability tooltip
fixed some issues with how invoke tracks your recently cast spells
it now always remembers the latest invoke spell even if it is one you already have. so if you have two and want to keep the oldest one, you can recast it and it will consider it the newest one.

jakiro
macropyre aoe increased from 200 to 225

juggernaut
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
blade dance critical strike chance rescaled from 10/20/25/35% to 15/20/25/35%

kunkka
ghost ship stun increased from 1 to 1.2 seconds
tidebringer cooldown rescaled from 16/12/8/4 to 13/10/7/4

lich
dark ritual cooldown rescaled from 30/27/24/21 to 35/30/25/20

lifestealer
reworked infest:
old:
lifestealer infests a target, hiding in it.
regains health based on the hp the unit has when he gets out of it
level 1 targets: allied and neutral units
level 2/3 targets: enemy, allied and neutral units
hp healed: current target hp (for level 1/2), max target hp (for level 3)
cooldown: 100/60/30
casting range: 150
mana cost: 50
note: this kills the infested unit.
new:
lifestealer infests a target, hiding in it. when he comes out of a unit, he deals damage to all nearby enemy units.
damage: 150/275/400
aoe: 700
targets: allied heroes, allied creeps, enemy creeps (including neutrals)
if the unit is an enemy creep, lifestealer will devour it first, gaining health equal to the unit's current hp.
cooldown: 100
casting range: 150
mana cost: 50

lina
aghanim's laguna blade cast range increased from 600 to 900

lone druid
spirit bear's demolish decreased from 60% to 40% bonus damage versus buildings

luna
lunar blessing rescaled from 8/16/24/32 to 14/20/26/32

lycan
wolves move speed increased from 400 to 400/420/440/460
wolves collision size reduced a bit

magnus
cast point reduced
empower cast range increased from 500 to 800
skewer's number of enemy units dragged rescaled from 2 to 1/2/3/4

meepo
added an aghanim's scepter upgrade:
creates an extra clone once the item is acquired. please note that the item is undroppable once the clone is created.

morphling
armor reduced by 2
replicate now has a visual time (player only) that counts down its duration
morph now has a visual effect

naga siren
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
nearby naga siren illusions now play the ensnare animation
critical strike replaced with rip tide
rip tide:
calls upon the power of the seas, creating an enchanted wave that deals damage and degrades enemy unit's armor for 8 seconds.
damage: 130/160/190/220
armor reduction: 2/3/4/5
duration: 8
aoe: 350
distance: 600
cooldown: 12
mana cost: 80/90/100/110
song of the siren reworked:
old:
sleeps all enemy units in range. slept units are invulnerable until the end of the spell.
duration: 6/7/8
aoe: 1000/1500/2000
cooldown: 120
mana cost: 200
new:
releases a melody around you the puts enemy units to sleep while they are in your range. units wake up if you leave the area or the duration of the melody runs out. slithice can choose to end the melody at any point.
aoe: 750 (units have to be continuously under the song to be slept)
duration: 6
cooldown: 180/120/60
mana cost: 100
note: ends when duration ends, units go out of range or naga siren dies. affects buildings.

nature's prophet
wrath of nature bounce count improved from 12/14/16 (14/16/18 w/scepter) to 16 (18/scepter)

necrophos
reaper's scythe reworked slightly:
the hp difference calculation is now processed after the stun duration is over, so any damage you do in between the start of the effect and the end is included in the final damage dealt. the stun duration is now reduced from 1.5 to 1 second.

night stalker
hunter in the night movement bonus rescaled from 15/20/30/35 to 20/25/30/35%
hunter in the night attack speed bonus rescaled from 20/35/55/75 to 30/45/60/75

outworld devourer
intelligence growth increased from 2.8 to 3.3

omniknight
purification cast range increased from 400 to 400/500/600/700

phoenix
icarus dive cooldown decreased from 40 to 30
icarus dive no longer makes phoenix spell immune. if he is disabled during it, he stops
sun ray no longer slows
sun ray damage from 10/20/30/40 + 5% to 15/30/45/60 + 4%
sun ray turn rate slightly improved
fire spirits now trigger in the area around you and your target when you use target fire spirits
the damage and heal from the two areas do not stack, you are only affected once

puck
base damage increased by 4
waning rift silence duration rebalanced from 0.1/1/2/3 to 0.75/1.5/2.25/3 seconds (41433)

pudge
rot damage increased from 25/50/75/100 to 35/60/85/110

queen of pain
sonic wave damage rescaled from 290/430/600 to 350/475/600

riki
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
blink strike cooldown rescaled from 30/20/10/5 to 20/15/10/5
smoke screen cast range increased from 350 to 425
smoke screen cooldown decreased from 15 to 13 seconds

sand king
armor increased by 1

shadow demon
disruption mana cost increased from 75 to 120
disruption cooldown rescaled from 16 to 25/22/19/16
disruption illusion duration rescaled from 6 to 5/6/7/8
changed shadow demon's hero model
this was his original model during development. the previous model will be used for another hero instead.

shadow shaman
base damage increased by 5
ether shock target count rescaled from 3/4/6/7 to 1/3/5/7
ether shock damage rescaled from 80/160/240/320 to 140/200/260/320
mass serpent wards are now automatically added to your unit selection upon cast (411025,1680)

silencer
movement speed increased from 290 to 300
curse of the silent cast range decreased from 900 to 800
glaives of wisdom cooldown from 2/0/0/0 to 0
last word is now muted when silencer is stunned (previously it was only when silenced)
last word no longer triggers on spell*attacks (frost arrows, burning spears, etc)
last word aoe decreased from 900 to 750
last word now steals a point of intelligence if silencer gets a killing blow on a hero
this is in addition if the hero died within the aoe. so if you kill a hero you will steal 2 intelligence points, otherwise you will steal 1.

slardar
amplify damage armor reduction increased from 5/10/15 to 8/12/16

slark
strength growth increased from 1 to 1.8
intelligence growth increased from 1.6 to 1.9
agility growth reduced from 2 to 1.5
essence shift now reduces each stat by 1 on attacks (no longer reduces the primary by 2)
essence shift agility bonus reduced from 4 to 3 per attack
essence shift duration increased from 15/30/45/60 to 15/30/60/120
essence shift permanently reduces each stat of a hero slark kills by 1 and he gains 3 agi permanently
pounce no longer hits non*hero units
pounce aoe increased from 85 to 95
pounce's speed fixed to be the same at all levels (426269)

spirit breaker
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75
greater bash now gives a 3 second 15% movement speed bonus whenever you land a bash
charge of darkness reworked:
old:
takes up to a few seconds to charge up and then starts moving towards his target. speed is based on how long it charged up for.
charge time: up to 4 seconds.
charge speed: up to 60%
stun: 1.4/1.8/2.2/2.6 seconds
cooldown: 40
mana cost: 75
casting range: global
notes:
1: gains vision (and truesight) over his target while casting.
2: becomes magic immunity only when fully charged.
3: target has a debuff indicator when barathrum is within 2500 distance.
4: speed bonus is retained for 2 seconds after impact.
5: becomes interrupted if the target dies, becomes decrepified or cycloned.
new:
immediately charges towards the targeted enemy unit. ignores pathing completely. stuns the target when it reaches it.
if the target dies, charge will automatically resume on another nearby visible unit.
while you are charging, all secondary units within 250 aoe of you are hit by a greater bash equal to its level.
primary target stun duration: 1.4/1.8/2.2/2.6
speed: 425/500/575/650
cooldown: 40
mana cost: 75
casting range: global
notes:
1: gains vision in a small area around the target.
2: if target dies, the charge will transfer to the nearest visible enemy unit
3: stops if you become stunned.
4: target has a debuff indicator when barathrum is within 2500 distance.

sven
great cleave aoe increased from 175 to 200

techies
aghanim's remote mine cast range decreased from 900 to 700
land mine limit increased from 15 to 20
suicide squad, attack! now gives techies xp for kills he gets with it
suicide squad, attack! cooldown from 75 to 180/170/160/150
suicide squad, attack! now causes techies death time to be reduced by 50%
detonate all subability of remote mine removed
based on techies player feedback, it was much more commonly used accidentally than for it's intended purpose. the new focused detonation ability or the group selection detonate fill the role better.

templar assassin
psi blades width increased from 70 to 80

terrorblade
movement speed increased from 300 to 310
sunder hp limit now applies to yourself
this is an improvement. it will no longer bring you down to the target's hp, it will follow the hp percentage restrictions. the main application of this is when it is used to heal an ally.
sunder cooldown rescaled from 200/120/60 to 160/110/60
metamorphosis reworked:
metamorphosis:
transforms to a powerful ranged demon with illusions.
attack range: 550
base attack time: 1.6 (melee is 1.5)
movement speed: 300 (melee is 310)
attack damage: 20/25/30/35 extra base damage [illusions benefit from this damage]
illusion count: 0/1/1/2
illusion outgoing damage: 0/10/15/20%
illusion incoming damage: 250%
duration: 30
cooldown: 70
mana cost: 100
note: when you transform, you gain selection of the illusions as well.
conjure image replaced with zeal:
zeal:
passive. grants bonus attack speed and hp regeneration.
attack speed: 20/30/40/50
hp regeneration: 2/3/4/5
note: attack speed bonus affects your metamorphosis illusions
soul steal replaced with reflection:
reflection:
terrorblade brings forth a dark reflection of all enemy units in a small area. affected units are slowed and attacked by their reflections for 5 seconds.
aoe: 350
duration: 5 seconds
slow: 20/25/30/35% (ms & as)
reflections outgoing damage: 35/45/55/65
reflections incoming damage: 0%
cast range: 600
mana cost: 75
cooldown: 20
note: reflections can only attack their source.
note 2: reflections are not normal illusions, they aren't clickable or selectable and take no damage. they are faded out visually to the enemy.

tidehunter
anchor smash reworked:
new:
spins around, dealing damage and giving a debuff to nearby enemies.
aoe: 400
damage: 75/125/175/225 (physical damage type)
attack damage reduction: 40%
duration: 6
cooldown: 7/6/5/4
mana cost: 30/40/50/60

tinker
heat-seeking missile now hits 2 units at all levels

tiny
tossed allied units no longer take damage (they used to take a portion of the damage)

treant protector
armor reduced by 1
nature's guise now gives the unit a 10% movement speed bonus
nature's guise keeps the target invisible for up to 1 second after leaving the proximity of a tree, except during the initial cast
nature's guise cooldown increased from 3 seconds to 10/8/6/4 seconds
overgrowth rebalanced:
old:
summons an overgrowth of damaging vines and branches. prevents all nearby enemies from moving or attacking and deals damage to each.
duration: 3/4/5
cooldown: 160
damage: 85 per second
aoe: 725
new:
summons an overgrowth of damaging vines and branches. prevents all nearby enemies from moving or attacking and deals damage to each.
duration: 3
cooldown: 100/95/90
damage: 70/100/130 per second
aoe: 725
living armor reworked:
living armor:
rooftrellen's presence infuses allied heroes and structures with a protective healing aura, increasing armor and regeneration. during the daytime, his power of nature is increased, causing the aura to extend globally.
aoe: 900 (global during the day)
hp regeneration: 2/3/4/5
armor: 1/2/3/4
forest sentinel replaced with leech seed
leech seed:
rooftrellen plants a life*sapping seed in his enemy, causing it to be slowed by 24% and have its life force drained over the next 3 seconds. nearby allied units are healed by the same amount.
slow: 24%
damage: 30/45/60/75 per pulse (magical damage type)
allied heal: 30/45/60/75 per pulse
pulses: 4
aoe: 500
mana cost: 110/120/130/140
cast range: 350
cooldown: 12

troll warlord
cast point reduced by 0.3
berserker rage transformation time removed (was 0.1 sec)
blind replaced with whirling axes:

troll is a master of the axe, learning axe skills in all forms of combat. when in melee form, summons magical axes to whirl around him in a circle, damaging enemies and causing them to have a 60% chance to miss attacks. when in ranged form, troll hurls a fistful of axes in cone formation. enemy units hit by the axes are slowed by 30%.
each have their own cooldowns and costs.
ranged form:
slow: 30%
duration: 3/3.75/4.5/5.25
range: 900
travels in a small cone
cooldown: 20
mana cost: 50
melee form:
miss rate: 60%
damage: 125/175/225/275
aoe: 450
duration: 4/5/6/7 seconds
cooldown: 12
mana cost: 50

tusk
ice shards now kills trees around the area it is created
snowball no longer moves faster based on the allies inside of it
it used to move at a rate of 1.5x your speed plus 50% of the speed of all allies. it now only moves at 1.5x your speed. the minimum speed for the snowball is 200.

underlord
model size slightly reduced
cast point decreased from 0.75 to 0.60
dark rift level 1 can now target units
expulsion reworked slightly
expulsion aoe now follows you around and is centered on your hero
expulsion no longer ministuns
expulsion search aoe increased from 475 to 600
expulsion damage/heal increased aoe from 375 to 600
expulsion now heals allies in the area it damages in (for half the amount 10/20/30/40)
pit of malice duration decreased from 1.5/2/2.5/3 to 1/1.5/2/2.5
pit of malice now deals 100 damage when it affects a unit
pit of malice now creates 5 corpses in the cast area
firestorm reworked:
old:
calls down 6 waves of fire that damage enemy units in an area. each wave deals initial damage and then burns enemies for 2 seconds.
number of waves: 6
damage per wave: 25/40/55/70
dps: 5/10/15/20 for 2 seconds
cast range: 750
aoe: 400
cooldown: 14
mana cost: 100/110/120/130
new:
channeling.
calls down 3 waves of fire that damage enemy units and structures in an area.
number of waves: 3
damage per wave: 55/80/105/130
dps: 15 for 3 seconds
deals 30% damage to buildings
cast range: 775
aoe: 450
cooldown: 16
mana cost: 100/110/120/130

ursa
enrage no longer triggers an additional fury swipes hit
earthshock damage increased from 70/120/170/220 to 90/140/190/240
fury swipes duration increased from 5 to 6 seconds
overpower cast time removed

vengeful spirit
aghanim's nether swap can now target creeps (339914)

venomancer
base hp regeneration increased from 0.25 to 0.75

viper
corrosive skin now stacks with poison attack

visage
base strength decreased from 25 to 22
strength growth increased from 2.2 to 2.4
soul assumption mana cost rescaled from 150 to 200/180/160/140
familiars hp improved from 300/400/500 to 300/450/600

warlock
fatal bonds link count increased from 2/3/4/5 to 3/4/5/6
fatal bonds casting range increased from 600 to 800
upheaval cooldown decreased from 65 to 50

weaver
armor reduced by 1
the swarm damage rescaled from 21/24/27/30 to 15/20/25/30

windranger
shackleshot cooldown increased from 10 to 12 seconds

witch doctor
death ward is automatically added to your unit selection upon cast
issuing a command to the ward will not cause your hero to be interrupted

wraith king
reincarnation now does a 700 aoe 3 second 30% slow around the area where he respawns
reincarnation delay decreased from 5/4.5/4 to 3 seconds

zeus
arc lightning cooldown decreased from 2.25 to 2
arc lightning mana cost improved from 65/72/79/87 to 65/70/75/80
items
added a new item:.
veil of discord

veil of discord
requires:
helm of iron will (950)
2x robe of the magi (900)
recipe (1250)
total: 3100
grants:
+5 armor
+5 hp regeneration
+12 intelligence
aoe active:
applies a debuff on all enemy units in an aoe, causing them to have reduced magic resistance for a duration.
magic amplification: 25%
aoe: 475
cast range: 800
duration: 15
mana cost: 75
cooldown: 30

drum of endurance
charges can now be refreshed by buying the recipe

animal courier

flying courier
added a short cooldown on courier and flying courier recipe buying to prevent accidental double buys
minimap indicator is now shown at the location where a courier dies
resume delivery ability added, upon use the courier will resume its previous deliver action (1680)
for example, if it was delivering an item to another player, and you interrupted it to do something, you could then resume it to deliver the items to its previous target.

assault cuirass
assault cuirass recipe cost decreased from 1500 to 1300

bloodstone
now starts with 5 charges
can no longer be disassembled
this is primarily due to the charge change above and preventing abuse

boots of travel
double clicking now teleports you to fountain
towers no longer stop attacking when you teleport to them
creeps no longer stop moving when you teleport to them
the unit you are teleporting on still has lowest ai priority

daedalus
critical strike chance increased from 20% to 25%

crystalys
critical strike chance increased from 15% to 20%

diffusal blade
purge cooldown decreased from 12 to 8
purge now removes ghost scepter's ghost form

ethereal blade
ether blast's slow increased from 45% to 60%
can now be disassembled

force staff
can no longer push units out of chronosphere

gem of true sight
stock cooldown increased from 6 to 8 minutes

scythe of vyse
mana regeneration decreased from 200% to 150%

hand of midas
gold is now reliable
mana cost removed (25*>0)
hand of midas now gives a constant amount of gold
it now gives a constant 190 bonus gold on all targets
some examples of what it previously it gave:

maximum of 208 gold if cast on the hellcaller
minimum of 92 gold if cast on the kobold tunneler or satyr trickster
154 gold if cast on a ranged creep
164 gold if cast on a polar furbolg ursa warrior
174 gold if cast on a centaur khan

healing salve
stock cooldown removed

heart of tarrasque
melee heroes now only have to wait 4 seconds after taking player damage for the regeneration to activate

pipe of insight
barrier's duration increased from 8 to 10 seconds

shadow blade
wind walk's bonus damage increased from 125 to 150

maelstrom
recipe cost decreased from 800 to 600 (417406)

mjollnir
recipe cost increased from 400 to 600
ias bonus increased from 70 to 80 to match it's components

necronomicon
warrior's last will damage rescaled from 200/400/600 to 400/500/600
archer's aura aoe increased to standard aura sizes (900)

orb of venom
orb of venom price decreased from 500 to 450

orchid malevolence
soul burn's damage recurrence increased from 20% to 25%

quelling blade
can now be sold

refresher orb
cooldown decreased from 210 to 160

ring of basilius
no longer interrupts your hero when toggled

sange
lesser maim is no longer an orb effect

sange and yasha
greater maim is no longer an orb effect

smoke of deceit
dispel aoe from heroes and towers increased from 850 to 950
stock cooldown increased from 10 to 12 minutes

desolator
corruption effect now works on buildings

urn of shadows
double clicking will now self-cast soul release
others
heroes now get xp if they get a kill outside of the standard xp range
increased the width of the sentinel ramp between roshan and the rune spawn
neutral spawn empty check no longer considers corpses in its spawn rules
improved courier deliver movement ai (harreke)
added buyback cost to observer scoreboard (430973)
added nerubian assassin to cm
added shadow demon to cm
rearranged group selection priority when selecting multiple shops (433891)
added new -stats (-st) command that replaces individual hero commands to show stats specific to the hero (replaces -gg, -aa, -int, -mines, -souls, -fs, -ha, -mc) (1680)
rebalanced all melee heroes between 100 and 128 range to be 128 range
these were 100 before: ck, naix, abaddon, lycan, balanar, pit lord, slardar, undying, rexxar, centaur, omniknight, panda, tide, magnus, spiritbreaker, bloodseeker, phantom assassin, terrorblade, spectre, meepo, ursa, magina, juggernaut, naga siren, phantom lancer, bristletback, ogre magi
these were 125 before: axe, sven, riki, clockwerk, dragon knight, dark seer
flying courier has a new model (frost wyrm)
animal courier has a new model (grunt, it's not easy being green!)
satyr hellcaller shockwave damage increased from 100 to 125
enemy wards now have a visual effect around them to allow you to more easily distinguish allied wards from enemy wards
shops now have an animation (for the player only) when you select them (431929)
fortify buildings glyph ability now prevents magic damage as well
added -disablehelp support for snowball
added a new command -msa to display the speed of all your allies (443896)
added a new debug command -respawn
swapped the location of the intelligence and agility taverns (410467)
-er (experimental runes) mode reworked, now enables runes spawn in both locations past 40 minutes
rearranged observer scoreboard to make it easier to see the creep stats for a hero
improved the ability display for split shot toggle (82888)
clockwerk goblin now has a visual effect with aghanim's scepter
invoker now has a visual effect with aghanim's scepter
thrall's class renamed from far seer to disruptor
tombstone now has a sound effect when cast
rikimaru's blink strike has a new special effect (4131913)
craggy exterior now has a visual effect when it stuns someone (118263)
omnislash has a new initial cast animation (430613)
nature's guise has a new icon (432222)
refraction now has two status icons to differentiate between attack and defense effects
shadowraze has a new visual effect
scream of pain has a new visual effect
added a new icon for fatal bonds
improved sonic wave sound and visuals (215238)
lina's attack old attack projectile is now restored
lina's fire hands visual effect have been improved
added a new epicenter visual effect (216828)
added a new hero icon for phoenix (378880)
added a new icon for overgrowth
added greek language support
bugs
fixed courier stopping and standing still in the middle of its delivery path if the hero disappears (astral imprisonment, disruption, etc)
fixed a bug with phase boots that could cause smoke of deceit invisibility to last a little bit extra after it should be revealed
fixed scream of pain not hitting fogged or invisible units
fixed item chest sometimes being hard to click when buying with full inventory at side shops (408678)
fixed courier command panel sometimes getting bugged if the courier is carrying certain items
fixed the collect items function causing an enemy gem to be teleported back to their base
fixed flying courier from being able to right click on a powerup to waste it
fixed natural order and ice vortex interaction with spell resistance items
fixed buyback wasting gold and cooldown if used while reviving with aegis
fixed creep spawn count increase timer starting from game load rather than creep spawn (421973)
fixed impetus damage cap reverting it to zero instead of remaining at the cap at long distances
fixed shackleshot not stunning the secondary target if it went into fog while the projectile was flying
fixed deaths during primal split from counting as suicides
fixed the selection type for mass serpent wards, death ward and plague wards so they behave like normal units from ui
fixed a rare bug that sometimes caused level 1-3 of necromastery to be a little higher than its max
fixed blur triggering on heroes with an invisibility buff
fixed a bug with tb disappearing from map
fixed sun ray continuing while reincarnating with aegis
fixed plasma field aoe damage not hitting invisible units
fixed desolator against swarm units
fixed desolator against seeking missile
fixed overcharge sometimes turning off by itself
fixed some rare bugs with time walk that could cause it to jump much further
fixed a bug with phase boots and spectral dagger
fixed a rare visual glitch possible with dream coil
fixed pudge being unable to cast meat hook when ethereal (443782)
fixed a bug with how stone gaze levels up
fixed a bug with how the slow on demonic purges levels up
fixed charge of darkness using up linken's sphere but continuing anyways
fixed meat hook from wasting linken's sphere
fixed laser's blind effect not getting removed by dark pact
fixed jinada charge getting wasted on structures
fixed armlet sometimes draining extra hp when you interact with your inventory
fixed smoke of deceit from getting temporarily applied if enemies are already in range
fixed being able to buy smoke and gem at enemy base (404663)
fixed lifestealer continuing to lose hp via armlet while he is infesting a unit
fixed some rare bugs with juggernaut becoming permanently magic immune and silenced
fixed a bug with rd that allowed you to make the heroes move
fixed some edges in the roshan area where you could place a ward
fixed gem allied visual effect sometimes not showing up
fixed urn of shadows ignoring linken's sphere
fixed ethereal blade ignoring linken's sphere
fixed primal roar not being blocked properly by linken's sphere
fixed waveform sometimes moving a little further than it should
added safety code to nether strike preventing cases that teleported sb into the enemy fountain
time lapse now starts remembering locations when weaver is picked instead of when it is skilled
fixed lots of old tooltip inconsistencies
see also
versions
patches
