gamepedia
help

sign in
register

navigation
search
(full list)
added new items:

crown

crown

yasha and kaya

yasha and kaya

kaya and sange

kaya and sange

ring of tarrasque

ring of tarrasque

holy locket

holy locket
removed items:

ring of aquila

ring of aquila
buffed:

batrider

batrider

bristleback

bristleback

clockwerk

clockwerk

disruptor

disruptor

faceless void

faceless void

jakiro

jakiro

legion commander

legion commander

lion

lion

luna

luna

monkey king

monkey king

nature's prophet

nature's prophet

nyx assassin

nyx assassin

oracle

oracle

puck

puck

queen of pain

queen of pain

riki

riki

shadow fiend

shadow fiend

shadow shaman

shadow shaman

skywrath mage

skywrath mage

slark

slark

sniper

sniper

techies

techies

tidehunter

tidehunter

timbersaw

timbersaw

underlord

underlord

viper

viper

warlock

warlock

witch doctor

witch doctor
nerfed:

arc warden

arc warden

axe

axe

broodmother

broodmother

earthshaker

earthshaker

enigma

enigma

io

io

morphling

morphling

necrophos

necrophos

phantom lancer

phantom lancer

phoenix

phoenix

terrorblade

terrorblade

weaver

weaver

zeus

zeus
reworked:

abaddon

abaddon

ancient apparition

ancient apparition

anti-mage

anti-mage

bane

bane

beastmaster

beastmaster

bloodseeker

bloodseeker

bounty hunter

bounty hunter

brewmaster

brewmaster

centaur warrunner

centaur warrunner

chaos knight

chaos knight

chen

chen

clinkz

clinkz

dark seer

dark seer

dazzle

dazzle

drow ranger

drow ranger

grimstroke

grimstroke

huskar

huskar

juggernaut

juggernaut

keeper of the light

keeper of the light

lich

lich

lifestealer

lifestealer

lone druid

lone druid

lycan

lycan

magnus

magnus

meepo

meepo

naga siren

naga siren

night stalker

night stalker

omniknight

omniknight

outworld devourer

outworld devourer

pangolier

pangolier

phantom assassin

phantom assassin

rubick

rubick

sand king

sand king

shadow demon

shadow demon

slardar

slardar

spirit breaker

spirit breaker

sven

sven

tiny

tiny

treant protector

treant protector

troll warlord

troll warlord

tusk

tusk

undying

undying
rebalanced:

crystal maiden

crystal maiden

death prophet

death prophet

doom

doom

dragon knight

dragon knight

earth spirit

earth spirit

elder titan

elder titan

ember spirit

ember spirit

medusa

medusa

ogre magi

ogre magi

razor

razor

templar assassin

templar assassin

vengeful spirit

vengeful spirit

venomancer

venomancer

wraith king

wraith king
dota 2:
2018-11-19
← version 7.19d
version 7.20b →
contents

1general
1
general

1.1denying
1.1
denying

1.2teleporting
1.2
teleporting

1.3neutrals
1.3
neutrals

1.4hero selection
1.4
hero selection

1.5armor
1.5
armor

1.6hero kill bounty xp
1.6
hero kill bounty xp

1.7mana and health regen
1.7
mana and health regen

1.8root mechanics
1.8
root mechanics

1.9cleave and splash
1.9
cleave and splash

1.10spell immunity and dispels
1.10
spell immunity and dispels

1.11towers and structures
1.11
towers and structures

1.12miscellaneous
1.12
miscellaneous

2heroes
2
heroes

3items
3
items

3.1new items
3.1
new items

3.2item changes
3.2
item changes

4see also
4
see also

5references
5
references
general
map has been reworked.
denying
denies no longer give the denier 25% xp.
creep denies now give the denier 20% of the gold bounty
melee creeps: 7-8 gold
ranged creeps: 9-11 gold
teleporting
added a new dedicated inventory slot to hold town portal scrolls
you still must purchase town portal scrolls from shops as usual
boots of travel: no longer shares cooldown with town portal scrolls. upon teleporting, +10 seconds are now added to your town portal scroll cooldown
neutrals
stacked neutral creeps now give the stacker 35% of the bounty instead of 25%
non-ancient neutrals now provide 5% more gold bounty
hero selection
removed daily bonus hero concept
random once again picks from the entire hero pool, but now ignores your 25 least played heroes
bonuses from randoming remain the same.
random can now only be used for the first two hero picks on your team
armor
changed the armor formula to: ( 0.052 * armor ) / ( 0.9+ 0.048 * armor)
updated various armor values to closely align with the new formula:
tier 1 towers: 17 to 12
tier 2 towers: 19 to 14
tier 3 towers: 19 to 14
tier 4 towers: 29 to 21
melee barracks: 18 to 13
ranged barracks: 12 to 9
ancient: 18 to 13
fillers: 14 to 10
shrines: 24 to 17
hero kill bounty xp
killing sprees now give an xp bonus ranging from 200 to 1250
reworked and simplified xp hero kill bounty system. no longer includes a team xp component
old:
new:
mana and health regen
reworked mana and hp regen from attributes. they are no longer multipliers of your regeneration values
mana regen: intelligence now provides 0.05 mana regeneration
mana regen: removed the 0.9 base mana regen value
now covered by base intelligence.
mana regen: rebalanced mana regen values based on the formula change
health regen: strength now provides 0.1 health regeneration
health regen: base regen values reduced by 1.5
now covered by base strength.
health regen: rebalanced health regen values based on the formula change
root mechanics
town portal scroll: can now be canceled and prevented by root
fixed inconsistencies between different root sources:
stasis trap now provides true sight
the following roots no longer interrupt channeling spells or the current action: dark troll ensnare, searing chains, naga siren ensnare, crystal maiden frostbite, entangling claws, nature's guise, and overgrowth
cleave and splash
cleave damage is now normal physical damage type, causing it to get reduced by the armor of each unit impacted
cleave abilities damage values have been rescaled
increased standard cleave area. distance increased from 625 to 650, final width increased from 330 to 360
affects: great cleave, empower, battle fury, and talents

templar assassin: psi blades can now spill off of illusions
changed how illusions' incoming damage is processed; it now happens at the final step
thus it won't splash over extra damage with things like psi blades.

fixed splash damage being affected by spell lifesteal and spell amplification
fixed splash damage not considering armor type
black dragon splash attack damage type changed from magical damage to physical damage
black dragon splash attack now does its full damage in the 250 aoe
instead of 100% at 150, 75% at 225, and 50% at 300.
similar adjustments to dragon knight's splash damage described below
spell immunity and dispels
the following abilities no longer pierce spell immunity: curse of avernus, acid spray, bloodrage, thirst, elder dragon form, lycan wolf cripple, epicenter, entangling claws, spiderling's poison sting, anchor smash, nature's guise, wave of terror, venomancer's poison sting, the swarm, maledict debuff, ghost frost attack, wrath of nature, netherward mana degen, life drain targeting, primal roar secondary knockback, requiem of souls, march of the machines collision, atrophy aura, tombstone, flesh golem, wall of replica slow, naga siren ensnare, dark troll summoner ensnare, wild axes, natural order, death pulse projectile, assassinate, shiva's guard aura, assault cuirass aura, tempest tornado aura, and orb of venom
black king bar: recipe cost increased from 1375 to 1450
poison sting can now be dispelled
hex state can now be removed by strong dispels
towers and structures
towers no longer gain extra armor per nearby enemy hero. tower health increased to account for some of this:
tier 1 towers health increased from 1600 to 1800
tier 2 towers health increased from 1600 to 1900
tier 3 towers health increased from 1600 to 2000
tier 4 towers health increased from 1600 to 2100
melee barracks health increased from 2000 to 2200
ranged barracks health increased from 1200 to 1300
ancient health increased from 4250 to 4500
miscellaneous
day/night cycle increased from 4 minutes to 5 minutes

scan no longer ignores units in the roshan pit

max attack speed increased from 600 to 700

default aura range increased from 900 to 1200
gem of truesight, heartstopper aura, and natural order remain unchanged.
removed movement speed modifiers from spawned creeps
previously different lanes would have faster/slower creeps during the first 7.5 minutes of the game.
added a new sound that gets played when all of a team's barracks are destroyed
[1]
opening secondary shops now highlights the items in the full shop ui, rather than switching to a filtered view
aoe of other wards are now shown during ward placement

added a new game state, leashed. leashed units follow the same rules as rooted units with regards to teleport and mobility based abilities, but can still use normal movement. the following abilities now apply the leashed state: pounce, dream coil and soulbind

self damage no longer disables things like clarity, bottle, blink, etc

lifesteal amount is no longer limited by the current hp of the target and uses the full damage you are dealing instead

backpack can no longer be manipulated while taunted

reduced the following movement speed talents: abaddon (25->20), axe (40->30), bane (65->50), batrider (50->40), bounty hunter (25->20), dazzle (50->40), enchantress (25->20), legion commander (50->40), lich (25->20), naga siren (25->20), nature's prophet (35->25), night stalker (45->40), nyx assassin (35->30), ogre magi (90->75), oracle (65->50), outworld devourer (35->30), pangolier (25->20), pugna (25->20), sand king (25->20), shadow demon (35->30), skywrath mage (25->20), techies (60->50), tidehunter (25->20), tinker (40->30), underlord (30->25)

intelligence heroes strength gain increased by 0.2
except for bane, outworld devourer, queen of pain, ogre magi, and zeus
killing an observer or sentry ward now prints out a notification in chat to your allies
respawn time for level 1/2/3/4 increased from 5/7/9/13 to 6/8/10/14
reverted a global turn rate change done in 7.00
was: * max turn rate speed increased by 15%
attribute growth values that had 2 decimal points have now been rounded up
shrines' sanctuary ability now additionally restores 2% hp/mana pool per second
as they no longer naturally scale with the intelligence mana regen changes
heroes

abaddon
base movement speed increased from 310 to 325
base agility increased by 6
base armor unchanged
mist coil projectile speed reduced from 1600 to 1300
curse of avernus:reworked
reworked
passive. slows the targets you attack by 10/15/20/25% for 4 seconds. if a target gets hit 4 times, they become cursed for 4 seconds and are silenced, slowed by 30/40/50/60% and all allied heroes that attack the target will receive a 40/60/80/100 as boost
you cannot start to increment the hit counter while they are cursed
level 25 talent changed from curse of avernus to +375 aoe mist coil

ancient apparition
ice vortex no longer has a self bonus
chilling touch:reworked:
reworked
it is now a passive autocast attack modifier.
grants you bonus attack range and causes your attack to deal heavy magic damage that slows movement for a brief period.
cooldown: 15/11/7/3 seconds.
damage: 50/85/120/155
slow: 100% for 0.5 seconds
attack range bonus: 60/120/180/240
mana cost: 30/50/70/90

anti-mage
removedupgrade
aghanim's scepter

aghanim's scepter
spell shield:removed
removed
counterspell:new ability
new ability
passively grants you 15/25/35/45% magic resistance and can be activated to provide a counterspell shield for 1.4 second. causes all spells that target you to be blocked and reflected onto the enemy.
cooldown: 15/11/7/3
mana cost: 40

arc warden
tempest double bounty increased from a fixed 180 gold/xp to 180/240/300
level 15 talent changed from +350 health to +300

axe
berserker's call armor bonus reduced from 40 to 30

bane
enfeeble:reworked
reworked
adds a debuff to the enemy unit, applying 36/44/52/60% negative status resistance to the target (which causes debuffs to last longer) and reducing the enemy's attack speed by 40/60/80/100. lasts 8 seconds. can be dispelled.
cast range: 1000
cooldown: 12/10/8/6
mana cost: 70/90/110/130
level 15 talent changed from enfeeble steals damage to enfeeble steals attack speed
level 20 talent changed from +100 enfeeble damage reduction to +100 enfeeble attack speed reduction

batrider
flaming lasso now does 20/40/60 damage per second
scepter no longer provides this. ticks every 1 second.

beastmaster
call of the wild:reworked
reworked
it no longer summons a neutral creep, and now has two separate hotkeys for the boar and the hawk. the hawk is a global point target ability that sends a permanently invisible uncontrollable hawk to that location starting from where you are. adjusted stats on the summoned units:
primal roar:
self movement boost increased from 30 to 40%
secondary units push distance from 300 to 450
secondary units push duration from 0.6 to 1.0
secondary unit slow duration now matches primary target (2/3/4 to 3/3.5/4)
secondary unit slow increased from 50 to 60
level 25 talent changed from +2 hawks summoned to -15s hawks cooldown

bloodseeker
thirst changed from giving attack damage to +30/45/60/75 attack speed
thirst movement speed increased from 7/18/29/40% to 12/24/36/48%
bloodrage incoming and outgoing damage reduced from 25/30/35/40% to 10/15/20/25%
bloodrage now does full amplification regardless of the distance (previously only did half for long distances)
blood rite damage from 120/160/200/240 to 125/175/225/275
rupture now deals 8% of current health as pure damage per 100 units moved. no longer lethal
rupture duration from 12 to 8/10/12
rupture cast range from 800 to 700/800/900
rupture cooldown from 60 to 70/60/50
level 20 talent changed from +18% rupture damage to +600 rupture cast range

bounty hunter
strength from 18+2.1 to 20+2.5
shadow walk no longer deals 30/60/90/120 damage. attacking out of invisibility now applies a 14/20/26/32% movement slow for 4 seconds
jinada:reworked
reworked
passive cooldown 12/9/6/3. causes your attack to deal +80/110/140/170 bonus attack damage. steals 12/18/24/30 unreliable gold from enemy heroes. your weapon glows when the attack is ready to strike
track:
movement speed bonus is now given to your hero only
now also causes attacks you do to the tracked enemy to crit for 1.4/1.6/1.8x
cast no longer breaks invisibility
gold radius from 925 to 1200
level 20 talent changed from +125% jinada critical strike to +90 jinada gold steal

brewmaster
intelligence gain increased from 1.3 to 1.6
base movement speed increased from 295 to 305
thunderclap mana cost from 90/105/130/150 to 90/100/110/120
drunken brawler:reworked
reworked
it is now a self active buff. lasts for 5 seconds. grants you 50/60/70/80% evasion and 80% chance to crit for 200/220/240/260%.
movement speed alternates between -20% and +40% while this is active
cooldown: 20/19/18/17
mana cost: 35/40/45/50
drunken haze:removed
removed
cinder brew:new ability
new ability
covers a target 400 aoe with alcohol, slowing them by 25% and causes them to have a 20/25/30/35% chance to attack themselves instead of the target. lasts 7 seconds. if the targets are hit by any fire based spells (including immolation from your fire spirit), the duration will refresh and they will ignite and burn for 10/25/40/55 dps.
cooldown: 20/18/16/14.
mana cost: 50.
self attack is not lethal
the following heroes have fire element damage: dragon knight, jakiro, phoenix, axe, doom, ember spirit, brewmaster, lina, ogre, batrider, wraith king, clinkz, invoker, warlock, underlord, and huskar
level 25 changed from +15% drunken brawler chance to +200% critical strike damage

bristleback
viscous nasal goo armor reduction increased from 1/1.4/1.8/2.2 to 1.4/1.8/2.2/2.6

broodmother
spiderling/spiderite magic resistance reduced from 50% to 40%

centaur warrunner
strength gain reduced from 4.3 to 4.0
hoof stomp damage reduced from 100/150/200/250 to 80/110/140/170
double edge damage changed from 175/250/325/400 to 150/200/250/300 + 40/60/80/100% of strength as damage
double edge cast point from 0.5 to 0.4
return has been renamed toretaliate
retaliate
retaliate no longer has a strength component
retaliate damage increased from 16/18/20/22 to 16/32/48/64
retaliate now gains charges each time you are attacked by an enemy hero or tower. can be activated, consuming the charges, to give you a percentage base attack damage increase for 20 **seconds. max stacks: 10.
provides 6/9/12/15% base damage increase per stack.
cooldown: 55/50/45/40
stampede cooldown increased from 90/75/60 to 110/100/90
stampede mana cost increased from 100 to 150
level 10 talent changed from +10% magic resistance to +20 movement speed
level 15 talent changed from +15% return strength damage to +50% double edge strength damage
level 15 talent changed from +75 damage to +30 base damage
level 20 talent changed from +300 double edge damage to +50 return damage

chaos knight
chaos strike:reworked
reworked
passive cooldown ability. lands a critical strike for a random amount, between min crit: 120% and max crit: 160/190/220/250%.
has 35/40/45/50% lifesteal for this hit.
cooldown: 8/7/6/5
reality rift no longer reduces armor
reality rift now moves the target a fixed amount of distance: 250/300/350/400
reality rift now maims the target applying a 15/25/35/45% movement and 30/50/70/90 attack speed slow for 2 seconds
reality rift cooldown rescaled from 18/14/10/6 to 20/15/10/5
reality rift cast range from 550/600/650/700 to 475/550/625/700
chaos bolt minimum damage rescaled from 75/100/125/150 to 60/90/120/150
chaos bolt maximum damage rescaled from 200/225/250/275 to 180/210/240/270
chaos bolt projectile speed reduced from 1000 to 700
phantasm: illusion count increased from 1/2/3 to 3
phantasm: illusion damage rescaled from 100% to 40/70/100%
phantasm: illusion duration reduced from 42 to 30
level 25 talent changed from -7 reality rift armor reduction to -2s chaos strike cooldown

chen
penitence projectile reduced from 2000 to 1400
penitence no longer amplifies damage
penitence now causes all allied units attacking the target unit to gain 30/60/90/120 attack speed
test of faith:removed
removed
divine favor:new ability
new ability
targets allied units, providing 7/13/19/25 hp regen, amplifying all regen and heals on the target by 25% and increasing attack damage by 10/20/40/80.
lasts 12 seconds
cooldown: 26/24/22/20
mana cost: 110
cast range: 800
holy persuasion now has a neutral creep level requirement of 4/5/6/6
holy persuasion minimum health increased from 700/800/900/1000 to 1000
holy persuasion now sends an allied unit anywhere on the map to you instead of sending them home. if the ally takes player based damage during this, the spell is interrupted
holy persuasion cooldown changed from 32/24/18/10 to 15
this used to be recall on keeper of the light, who no longer has it
level 15 talent changed from -10s test of faith cooldown to -10s divine favor cooldown

clinkz
death pact:removed
removed
burning army:new ability
new ability
uses vector targeting. spawns 4/5/6 fiery skeleton archers along a 1300 line
skeletons attack using searing arrows, have your base damage, are immobile and take 2 hits to kill from a hero. they only attack enemy heroes (like wd ward, but killable)
attack range matches your hero
spawn at 0.8 second intervals
cast range: 800
cooldown 110
mana cost: 125/175/225
lasts 20 seconds
base attack time: 1.8/1.65/1.5

clockwerk
rocket flare projectile speed increased from 1750 to 2250
power cogs knockback distance increased from 250 to 300
power cogs knockback duration increased from 0.85 to 1
power cogs damage from 50/100/150/200 to 50/125/200/275
power cogs mana burn from 50/100/150/200 to 50/80/110/140

crystal maiden
base damage increased by 2
frostbite no longer has an interrupt
same as other roots changed, still interrupts teleports
frostbite cast range increased from 525 to 550
freezing field no longer has a 0.3 cast point

dark seer
surge duration rescaled from 3/4.5/6/7.5 to 6
surge cooldown rescaled from 13/12/11/10 to 16/14/12/10
surge now causes the target to be unslowable
surge speed changed from 550 to +36/54/72/90%
surge now causes the target to ignore movement speed limit
surge now causes the target to ignore unit collisions
wall of replica now uses vector targeting to cast
wall of replica cast point reduced from 0.4 to 0.2
wall of replica cast range increased 500/900/1300 to 1300
wall of replica always now slows heroes touching the wall continuously, and the debuff lingers for 0.75 seconds after leaving the wall
previously only reapplied the slow when the illusion died
wall of replica slow reduced from 75% to 50/60/70%

dazzle
poison touch mana cost increased from 80 to 80/90/100/110
poison touch debuff now stacks
weave:removed
removed
bad juju:new ability
new ability
passive ability. grants you 30/40/50% cooldown reduction. anytime you cast a spell, all enemies within a 1200 aoe around you lose 2/2.25/2.5 armor for 10 seconds.
debuffs stack and refresh duration
doesn't affect roshan
shadow wave cooldown increased from 12/10/8/6 to 13/11/9/7
level 25 talent changed from +0.5 weave armor per second to +0.5 bad juju armor reduction
level 25 talent changed from -4s shadow wave cooldown to +40% poison touch slow

death prophet
movement speed increased from 305 to 310
spirit siphon now drains 4/6/8/10% speed (instead of only slowing for 5/10/15/20%)

disruptor
thunder strike damage increased from 40/60/80/100 to 45/70/95/120

doom
base attack range increased from 150 to 175
devour no longer has a restriction on consuming while another unit is being consumed
devour now gives you 5/10/15/20 hp regen per second while the creep is being consumed
devour now takes a constant 80 seconds to consume a creep
devour can now be toggled off to not steal the creep ability
if autocast is on, it'll steal, otherwise it won't
scorched earth no longer heals
scorched earth cooldown reduced from 55 to 55/50/45/40
scorched earth damage increased from 16/24/32/40 to 20/30/40/50
level 10 talent changed from +10 scorched earth damage/heal to +20 scorched earth damage

dragon knight
elder dragon form splash attack now does 75% damage in the 300 aoe (instead of 100% in 50 aoe, 50% in 150 aoe, 25% in 250 aoe)
elder dragon form splash attack no longer does partial damage if the attack misses

drow ranger
precision aura now provides attack speed based on 20/36/52/68% of your agility, rather than damage based on 10/20/30/40% of your agility
marksmanship:reworked
reworked
now provides a 20/30/40% chance to land a piercing attack that cannot be evaded and strikes through the enemy's defenses, ignoring their armor entirely. instantly kills creeps. gets disabled if an enemy hero is within 400 range of you
level 20 talent changed from +20 marksmanship agility to +25% evasion
level 25 talent changed from +20% precision aura damage to +25% precision aura attack speed

earthshaker
fissure cooldown increased from 18/17/16/15 to 21/19/17/15

earth spirit
strength gain increased from 3.5 to 3.8
rolling boulder changed from an 80% slow for 0.4/0.6/0.8/1.0 seconds to a stun for 0.4/0.6/0.8/1.0
rolling boulder stun duration lasts an extra 0.4/0.6/0.8/1.0 seconds when using a rock
boulder smash changed from a stun for 0.5/1/1.5/2 seconds to an 80% slow for 1.25/2.5/3.25/4 seconds
boulder smash damage increased from 50/100/150/200 to 105/170/235/300
stone remnant max charges increased from 6 to 7
magnetize aoe increased from 300 to 350
level 25 talent changed from +1s boulder smash stun duration to +0.75s rolling boulder stun duration

elder titan
astral spirit damage reduced from 60/90/120/150 to 50
astral spirit return speed increased from 600 to 800
astral spirit attack damage per hero from 15/30/45/60 to 20/40/60/80
astral spirit now provides +1.5/3/4.5/6 armor per hero hit and +0.5 per creep
astral spirit movement speed increased from 5% to 7%
astral spirit movement speed cap increased from 30% to 40%
astral spirit bonus duration increased from 9 to 10 seconds
level 25 talent changed from +100% lifesteal to astral spirit grants spell immunity

ember spirit
fire remnant now does damage along the way (at half radius) instead of only at the destination
only hits enemies once per remnant.

enigma
base movement speed reduced from 300 to 290

faceless void
time lock now causes faceless void to land a free second attack while the target is locked in place. deals bonus 30/40/50/60 damage and bashes for 0.75 seconds
level 15 talent from +100 time lock damage to +70

grimstroke
enabled grimstroke in captains mode
soulbind now applies a leashed state to the targets, disallowing teleportation and mobility based abilities
soulbind duration reduced from 6/8/10 to 6/7/8
phantom's embrace creature now gets closer to the target before latching on
ink swell now does its maximum impact based on the duration it hit any hero, rather than amount of dps dealt dealt to all heroes combined (scales linearly from 0 to 3 seconds)
ink swell max stun duration reduced from 2.2/2.8/3.4/4 to 2/2.6/3.2/3.8
level 20 talent changed from +2 hits to kill phantom to +1

huskar
berserker's blood no longer gives magic resistance. now provides health regen up to 20/40/60/80% of strength based on missing health
berserker's blood now ramps up faster when lower health
inner vitality:removed
removed
inner fire:new ability
new ability
in a fiery rage, knocks all enemies within 500 range away from you, dealing 100/155/210/265 damage and disarming them for 1.75/2.5/3.25/4 seconds
enemies are knocked back to 550 range away from you
knockback duration: 0.6
cooldown: 18/16/14/12 seconds
mana cost: 75/100/125/150
level 15 talent increased from +15% lifesteal to +20%
level 15 talent increased from +10 burning spears dps to +15
level 20 talent increased from +15 strength to +20
level 25 talent increased from +150 attack range to +175

io
spirits cooldown increased from 26/22/18/14 to 26/24/22/20

jakiro
macropyre damage now lingers on the affected units for 2 seconds

juggernaut
agility increased by 10 (base damage unchanged)
changed how omnislash does the strikes from just physical damage nukes (with occasional invisible attacks depending on attack speed) to all full real attacks that can proc your crit and items. lasts 3/3.25/3.5 seconds and attacks at 1.8x your attack rate. provides +30/45/60 damage. scepter lasts 4/4.25/4.5 seconds and 70 cooldown
omnislash no longer constantly issues self interrupts during each attack (would cause it to drop your orders)
omnislash no longer instantly kills creeps

keeper of the light
mana leak:removed
removed
spirit form:removed
removed
recall has been moved to chen
illuminate cooldown increased from 10 to 11
illuminate aghanim's scepter effect now just heals during the day. this turns your hero into the spirit form visually during daytime.
chakra magic:reworked
reworked
restores 80/160/240/320 mana and removes 3/4/5/6 seconds off of basic abilities currently on cooldown.
cooldown: 20/18/16/14
blinding light:reworked
reworked
now a basic ability. causes everyone in a 600 aoe to be blinded, missing 70% of their attacks for 3/4/5/6 seconds. knocks targets back 350 units and deals 50/100/150/200 damage.
cooldown: 30/25/20/15
mana cost: 100/125/150/175
cast range: 550/600/650/700
will-o-wisp:new ability
new ability
ultimate ability. spawns an attackable light entity, ignis fatuus. the light flickers on for 1.3 seconds and off for 1.75 seconds
enemies within a 650 radius are hypnotized and forced to look at it whenever it is emitting light, unable to act
the light entity can be killed with 4/5/6 attacks, otherwise it will flicker 3/4/5 times before going away
dormant for 1 second before the first flicker begins
cooldown: 120
cast range: 900
mana cost: 200/300/400
level 25 talent changed from +2s mana leak stun to +2 will-o-wisp flickers

legion commander
duel wins automatically casts press the attack on you.

lich
intelligence increased from 16 + 3.3 to 20 + 3.6
frost nova mana cost reduced from 125/150/170/190 to 105/130/155/180
sacrifice:removed
removed
sinister gaze:new ability
new ability
channeling single target. causes the enemy to slowly walk towards you (moves to a point 32/38/44/50% between you two).
lasts up to 1.6/1.9/2.2/2.5 seconds
cast range: 500/525/550/575
cooldown: 30
mana cost: 120/130/140/150
ice armor:removed
removed
frost shield:new ability
new ability
targets self or an ally and applies a frost shield. reduces physical attack damage taken by 30/40/50/60% for 6 seconds
every second, all enemies within a 600 aoe will take 20/30/40/50 damage and be slowed by 35% for 0.5 seconds
cooldown: 30/25/20/15
mana cost: 100/110/120/130
level 20 talent changed from 180 gold/min to +2s frost shield
level 20 talent reduced from +175 cast range to +150
level 25 talent increased from ice armor provides +30 hp regen to frost shield provides +60 hp regen

lifestealer
feast changed from 4.5/5.5/6.5/7.5% of current health to 1.75/2.5/3.25/4% of max health
level 25 talent changed from +2% current health to +1% max health

lion
mana drain slow increased from 16/19/22/25% to 20/24/28/32%
finger of death now gets stronger with each kill. gains +50 damage per hero kill. if the enemy dies within 3 seconds of being hit by the ability, the bonus is still granted

lone druid
base movement speed increased from 320 to 340
spirit bear movement speed increased from 320/330/340/350 to 340/350/360/370
spirit bear attack backswing time reduced from 0.67 to 0.4
spirit bear attack damage increased from 35/45/55/65 to 35/50/65/80
spirit bear now has a level 1 ability, defender. passively causes 30% of the damage lone druid takes to be instead dealt to the spirit bear if you are within the leash range
rabid:removed
removed
spirit link:new ability
new ability
grants both of you 30/50/70/90 attack speed and causes 40/50/60/70% of damage you deal to restore life to your spirit bear, and damage your spirit bear deals to restore life to you. **duration: 10 seconds
cooldown: 42/34/26/18
mana cost: 50/60/70/80

luna
lunar blessing now provides +8/14/20/26 primary attribute bonus as the aura bonus, rather than bonus damage
level 15 talent changed from +24 lunar blessing damage to +14 lunar blessing attributes

lycan
howl:reworked
reworked
now grants +21/34/47/60 attack speed, +3/4/5/6 armor and +4/6/8/10 hp regen to all player controlled units on the map.
lasts 9 seconds
cooldown: 50/45/40/35
mana cost: 25/30/35/40

magnus
skewer cooldown reduced from 25 to 26/24/22/20
shockwave:reworked
reworked
releases a wave towards a target point, pulls units towards it slightly and deals 75/150/225/300 damage.
slows enemies by 60% for 0.75 seconds.
width: 200
distance: 1200
projectile speed: 900
pull duration: 0.2
mana cost: 90/100/110/120
cooldown: 14/13/12/11

medusa
stone gaze no longer grants enemies +100% magic resistance
stone gaze no longer instantly kills illusions
mystic snake no longer changes damage type against stone gazed enemies

meepo
base movement speed increased from 310 to 320
geostrike:removed
removed
ransack:new ability
new ability
each attack steals 8/12/16/20 health from your enemy heroes (and 4/6/8/10 from creeps) and heals all meepos by the same amount
has no range limit. this hurts enemies as well. does not affect roshan.
clones now only drain 50% of normal xp from the area
level 10 talent reduced from +20 damage to +15

mirana
leap now causes the direction mirana is facing to point towards the leap direction

monkey king
mischief will now always transform into a courier when nearby another courier
mischief now grants you 0.3 seconds of invulnerability when transforming into another unit
mischief cooldown increased from 3 to 20

morphling
waveform cooldown increased from 14/13/12/11 to 17/15/13/11

naga siren
mirror image duration reduced from 30 to 24
mirror image cooldown reduced from 40 to 45/40/35/30
mirror image mana cost rescaled from 70/80/90/100 to 70/85/100/115
mirror image incoming damage reduced from 550/500/450/400% to 475/450/425/400%
rip tide:reworked
reworked
now a passive attack chance ability. gives a chance that your attack will trigger a rip tide that deals aoe damage and reduces armor. illusions can proc this.
chance: 17%
duration: 4
armor reduction: 2/4/6/8
damage: 30/40/50/60
aoe: 300

nature's prophet
treants experience bounty reduced from 30 to 20
treants gold bounty reduced from 21 to 16

necrophos
base attack range reduced from 550 to 500
heartstopper aura now provides the unit kill regeneration instead of death pulse (if necro himself gets the kill)

night stalker
crippling fear:reworked
reworked
it is now an activated 375 range aura that silences all enemies while they are nearby.
aura lasts 5/6/7/8 seconds (3 during day).
no longer has a miss chance.
cooldown: 30/25/20/15.
mana cost: 50
since this is an aura, it can't be dispelled with manta
hunter in the night no longer has an active.
darkness:removed
removed
dark ascension:new ability
new ability
transform into a stronger flying creature that has +50/100/150 bonus damage and 900 unobstructed vision. lasts for 30 seconds. daytime is turned to night during this.
cooldown: 160/140/120
mana cost: 125/175/225
level 25 changed from -8s crippling fear cooldown to -40s dark ascension cooldown

nyx assassin
vendetta now applies a break debuff on the target for 4 seconds

ogre magi
multicast now affects targeted offensive items. will cause the item to cast again at a different random enemy unit
multicast no longer provides passive improvements to the base abilities
ignite cast range increased from 700 to 700/800/900/1000
ignite base cast launches two projectiles (one at the primary target, and one at the closest unit to it)
fire blast cooldown rescaled from 12 to 12/11/10/9
bloodlust cooldown reduced from 20 to 20/18/16/14
bloodlust movement speed reduced from 10/12/14/16% to 8/10/12/14%

omniknight
purification can now be cast on spell immune units
repel:removed
removed
heavenly grace:new ability
new ability
targets an allied unit and applies a strong dispel, and then increases status resistance by 50/60/70/80% and health regeneration by 8/12/16/20 for 8 seconds.
cooldown: 17/16/15/14
mana cost: 75
cast range: 500
guardian angel aoe increased from 600 to 1200
guardian angel cooldown reduced from 180/170/160 to 160/150/140
level 25 talent changed from +3s repel duration to -8s heavenly grace cooldown

oracle
fortune's end damage increased from 90/120/150/180 to 120/150/180/210

outworld devourer
arcane orb now splashes its bonus damage in a 175 aoe around the target
arcane orb no longer does bonus damage to illusions
essence aura:removed
removed
equilibirum:new ability
new ability
self buff. causes all spell damage you deal to restore 60/80/100/120% of damage back as mana and slow enemies by 8/16/24/32% for 1.75 seconds.
lasts 7 seconds
cooldown: 20
mana cost: 50
level 15 talent changed from +15% essence aura chance to +6 armor

pangolier
heartpiercer:removed
removed
lucky shot:new ability
new ability
gains a 20% chance to apply a debuff for 2/3/4/5 seconds that slows the target by 40% and causes the target to be either silenced or disarmed.
multiple instances of this debuff stack

phantom assassin
phantom strike cooldown rescaled from 14/11/8/5 to 11/9/7/5
phantom strike cast point reduced from 0.3 to 0.25
phantom strike attack speed rescaled from 130 to 100/125/150/175
phantom strike no longer has an attack limit
phantom strike attack speed bonus now lasts for 2.5 seconds
phantom strike mana cost rescaled from 50 to 35/40/45/50
phantom strike attack speed bonus no longer depends on attacking the specific target
blur:reworked
reworked
non-evasion passive component has been changed into an active (evasion component is unchanged). causes enemies to be unable to see you (like smoke) until you are within 600 units of an enemy hero or buildings.
does not dispel when attacking
lingers around for 0.75 seconds before going away after being near an enemy hero
lasts 25 seconds
cooldown: 60/55/50/45
mana cost: 20

phantom lancer
phantom lance slow reduced from 10/20/30/40% to 10/18/26/34%
juxtapose incoming damage increased from 600% to 650%

phoenix
icarus dive slow rescaled from 28% to 19/22/25/28%

puck
dream coil now applies a leashed state to the targets, disallowing teleportation and mobility based abilities
level 15 talent increased from +50 attack damage to +90
level 15 talent increased from +8% spell amplification to +15%

pudge
flesh heap no longer gives magic resistance
flesh heap now grants 3/6/9/12 hp regen
dismember strength based damage increased from 30/45/60% to 30/60/90%

queen of pain
sonic wave now knocks units back 350 units over 1.4 seconds
does not stun

razor
unstable current no longer slows or purges a random enemy unit every 5 seconds
unstable current now deals 60/80/100/120 damage to every enemy unit within 500 aoe every 6/5/4/3 seconds
plasma field now applies a slow on units it hits, minimum 5% maximum 25/30/35/40% for 1.5 seconds. slow instances stack (plasma hits enemies twice)
level 25 talent changed from -3s unstable current to +200 unstable current damage

riki
blink strike cooldown rescaled from 16/12/8/4 to 10/8/6/4
blink strike damage rescaled from 100 to 75/90/105/120

rubick
base damage increased by 3
agility increased from 14 + 1.6 to 19 + 2.1
intelligence gain increased from 2.4 to 2.7
null field:removed
removed
arcane supremacy:new ability
new ability
passive. gains 14/18/22/26% spell amplification and causes all debuffs you apply to the enemy to last 20/28/36/44% longer
spell steal ability cast points now have a min of 0.15 instead of 0
level 15 talent increased from +100 cast range to +125
level 20 talent changed from +5% null field to -5s fade bolt cooldown
level 25 talent changed from +75% spell amp for stolen spells to +50%

sand king
sand storm is no longer a channeled ability. the sand storm and the invisibility ends immediately once you leave the area. attacking or casting temporarily reveals you for 0.7 seconds
sand storm aoe changed from 525 to 350/450/550/650
sand storm damage rescaled from 40/60/80/100 to 25/50/75/100
sand storm cooldown rescaled from 34/26/18/10 to 34/28/22/16
sand storm duration reduced from 50 to 20/25/30/35
sand storm visual effects updated slightly
epicenter aoe growth now always increases by 50 per pulse, instead of sometimes 25/50/75

shadow demon
soul catcher:reworked
reworked
targets a 175/200/225/250 aoe area. causes all units in the area to lose 25/30/35/40% of their current health, and gain half of it back after 10 seconds.
cooldown: 26/24/22/20
cast range: 700
mana cost: 110
dispelling this gains your health back as well
disruption illusions health is now determined at the start of the cast
disruption duration increased from 2.5 to 2.75

shadow fiend
base armor increased by 1

shadow shaman
mass serpent wards now spawn in a circle, with a slightly bigger empty spot in the middle
mass serpent wards now has an aoe spawn indicator

skywrath mage
concussive shot now hits a creep if there are no nearby enemy heroes
deals 75% damage to creeps

slardar
base armor increased by 1
bash of the deep:reworked
reworked
passive. every 4th attack your hero does (on any target) applies a bash for 1/1.1/1.2/1.3 seconds dealing 75/125/175/225 physical damage
slithereen crush:
stun duration reduced from 1.25/1.5/1.75/2 to 1 second.
attack and movement slow duration increased from 2 to 3/4/5/6 and slow amount increased from 20 to 20/25/30/35%.
damage increased from 75/125/175/225 to 80/140/200/260
level 15 talent changed from +100 bash damage to +75
level 25 talent changed from +15% bash chance to +1.5s slithereen crush stun

slark
turn rate improved from 0.6 to 0.7
pounce now applies a leashed state to the target, disallowing teleportation and mobility based abilities
shadow dance duration rescaled from 4 to 4/4.5/5
a hero dying with essence shift debuff on them causes slark to permanently steal 1 agility

sniper
take aim:reworked
reworked
can now be activated to double your attack range for your next attack. goes on cooldown after the attack is used.
cooldown: 15/12/9/6
mana cost: 30

spirit breaker
nether strike can no longer be cast when rooted
charge of darkness no longer moves at a fixed speed. it now unlocks the movement speed cap and adds 300/325/350/375 movement speed
previously it fixed your speed to 600/650/700/750
fixed charge of darkness not using the movement speed for the impact damage
greater bash no longer gives you movement speed
greater bash damage reduced from 12/24/36/48 to 16/24/32/40%
empowering haste:removed
removed
bulldoze:new ability
new ability
upon activation, grants your hero +12/18/24/30% movement speed and +30/40/50/60% status resistance for 8 seconds.
cooldown: 22
mana cost: 25/30/35/40
casting bulldoze does not interrupt charge of darkness
level 20 greater bash talent reduced from 30% to 15%
level 20 talent changed from +400 charge speed to -7s bulldoze cooldown

sven
warcry:reworked
reworked
now grants you and nearby allied heroes bonus movement speed and an hp shield that blocks attack damage based on the shield's health.
damage blocked calculated post armor reduction
lasts 10 seconds
buff ends if the shield is consumed
movement speed: 8/12/16/20%
attack shield health: 100/200/300/400
aoe: 700
cooldown: 36/32/28/24
mana cost: 40

techies
base movement speed increased from 270 to 315
base intelligence increased by 2

templar assassin
level 20 talent changed from refraction dispels to meld dispels
level 25 talent changed from psi blades spill paralyzes to 1.5s meld hit bash

terrorblade
sunder can no longer pierce spell immunity
level 20 talent reduced from -10s reflection cooldown to -8

tidehunter
anchor smash now attacks every unit in the area with a bonus 45/90/135/180 damage on top of your attack
ravage damage increased from 200/290/380 to 200/300/400
level 10 talent increased from +80 gush damage to +100

timbersaw
chakram projectile damage no longer ignores ancients
whirling death is now always pure damage
whirling death damage changed from 100/150/200/250 to 90/120/150/180
whirling death stat reduction rescaled from 15% to 12/13/14/15%
whirling death now deals 10/14/18/22 extra damage per tree cut down
level 25 talent increased from +8% whirling death to +12%

tiny
tree grab area damage no longer works when denying units
tree grab cooldown increased from 24/20/16/12 to 27/22/17/12
grow no longer provides 30/40/50% status resistance
grow armor increased from 5/10/15 to 7/16/25
avalanche:reworked
reworked
the units in the area are now continuously hit by short ministuns and damage every 0.3 seconds. each hit stuns for 0.2 seconds
duration increased from 1 to 1.8
aoe increased from 275 to 400
cooldown reduced from 23/21/19/17 to 23/20/17/14
total damage rescaled from 120/180/240/300 to 90/160/230/300
toss avalanche damage bonus increased from 2x to 3x (the entire avalanche duration is no longer covered by toss)
level 10 talent changed from +20% magic resistance to +20 movement speed
level 25 talent changed from -12s avalanche cd to -9s (due to avalanche cooldown improvement)

treant protector
nature's guise:reworked
reworked
passive. has a 4.75/4/3.25/2.5 second fade delay, taking damage resets the counter.
grants you invisibility, treewalking ability, and 10/15/20/25% movement speed bonus as long as you are within 265 distance of a tree.
has a 0.75 linger duration.
attacking a unit out of this roots the target for 0.4/1/1.6/2.2 seconds and deals a total of 30/80/130/180 damage during the root.

troll warlord
base damage increased from 38-56 to 44-56
berserker's rage now applies an ensnare instead of a bash
berserker's rage proc chance increased from 10% to 10/12/14/16%
basher and abyssal blade are no longer restricted items
fervor stack limit increased from 7 to 12
fervor now starts at 0 stacks when attacking a new unit
fixed fervor incrementing when missing attacks
battle trance:reworked
reworked
now causes you to go into an uncontrollable trance, forcing you to attack the closest targets in a 900 aoe. during this trance, you are unslowable and cannot die.
grants +140/170/200 attack speed, +30/35/40% movement speed and +40/60/80% lifesteal.
lasts 6.5 seconds.
you gain normal vision over the target you are currently locked on.
cooldown: 90
mana cost: 150
level 25 talent changed from battle trance basic dispel to battle trance strong dispel (can be cast while stunned)

tusk
frozen sigil:removed
removed
tag team:new ability
new ability
activatable aura. lasts 5 seconds. causes affected enemies to take 25/50/75/100 more physical damage from attacks and be slowed by 75% for 0.5 seconds.
aoe: 350
cooldown: 15
mana cost: 40/50/60/70
tusk can crit off this physical damage

underlord
atrophy aura now provides a permanent +2/3/4/5 bonus damage when a hero dies under the aura

undying
base movement speed reduced from 305 to 295
flesh golem:reworked
reworked
no longer amplifies damage. slow is now a constant 24/32/40% in 375 aoe (instead of 1% to 20% based on distance up to 750 range).
enemy units in 400 aoe lose 7% of their current hp per second as magic damage.
you gain +400/1000/1600 health when in this mode.
cooldown: 110
flesh golem model size increased a bit

ursa
fixed overpower not consuming attack count when an attack is evaded

vengeful spirit
vengeance aura no longer creates illusions of dying allies
vengeance aura now creates the scepter effect on dying as a base mechanic, without the ability to cast spells. gaining scepter unlocks casting spells
netherswap cast range rescaled from 700/950/1200 to 700/850/1000
netherswap now has 2 charges with 90/80/70 second replenish time (scepter still reduces this to 10 seconds.)

venomancer
plague wards collision size increased
level 15 talent changed from +200 cast range to gale hero impact summons 2 wards
level 20 talent changed from gale hero impact summons 2 wards to +15% spell lifesteal

viper
nethertoxin aoe increased from 300 to 350
nethertoxin damage rescaled from 20/30/40/50 to 20/35/50/65

warlock
fatal bonds now bounces from unit to unit, rather than just searching units near the target
fatal bonds no longer ignores units in fog of war

weaver
the swarm units now have higher attack priority (follows same rules as phantom's embrace)
geminate attack cooldown increased from 7/6/5/3 to 9/7/5/3

witch doctor
death ward damage increased from 60/105/150 to 75/125/175

wraith king
skeletons health reduced from 350 to 250
skeletons now reincarnate 3 seconds after dying the first time

zeus
nimbus is no longer automatically selected when hitting tab
nimbus's lightning bolt no longer benefits from cooldown reductions on your hero
items
all item-based movement speed bonuses are now rebalanced around being a percentage rather than a constant addition
numbers below are designed around being similar with a base of 300 speed, with boot items being -5 and eul's being -10 of their old values.
new items

crown
added a new basic item: crown, +4 all stats, 450 gold (available in side shop). used in items that previously required bracer, wraith band, and null talisman

yasha and kaya
added a new item: yasha and kaya

kaya and sange
added a new item: kaya and sange
rebalanced sange/yasha/kaya and sange and yasha stats

ring of tarrasque
added a new basic item: ring of tarrasque. costs 700 gold. grants +3.75 hp regen and +150 health. upgrades into heart of tarrasque and holy locket

holy locket
added a new item: holy locket. passive. causes all heals and hp regen you provide to be amplified by 25%
item changes

phase boots
reworked to no longer have an active. now passively gives you movement speed bonus, collision phasing and turn rate anytime you issue an attack to a target. buff dispels whenever you move elsewhere and cancel your attack. maximum range of 900 for attack orders.
will still kick in if you issue the orders out of 900 range and then walk in.
this has no cooldown. buff lingers for 0.5 seconds
phase movement speed bonus on ranged heroes reduced from 13% to 10%
reworked phase boots recipe:

power treads
attribute bonus increased from 10 to 12
reworked power treads recipe:

tranquil boots
no longer gets disabled by attacking creeps

heaven's halberd
now provides +14% status resistance instead of maim

sange and yasha
now provides +16% status resistance instead of maim

sange
now provides +12% status resistance instead of maim
recipe cost reduced from 700 to 650

yasha
recipe cost reduced from 700 to 650

kaya
recipe increased from 500 to 650

solar crest
reworked recipe and bonuses
active ability: can be cast on allies or enemies, removing your own +12 armor bonus. grants allies +70 attack speed, +10% movement speed, +12 armor. on enemies it applies -70 attack speed, -10% movement speed, -12 armor
casting this removes only the bonus armor from your hero.

ring of aquila
removed ring of aquila from the game
bracer, wraith band and null talisman can no longer be upgraded into other items
bracer/null/wraith recipe increased from 165 to 210
bracer/null/wraith primary stat from +7 to +8

bracer
now gives +6% magic resistance

wraith band
now gives +8 attack speed

null talisman
now gives +3% spell amp
the following recipes have been updated with the removal of bracer, wraith band and null talisman as item components

hurricane pike
now has a 450 gold recipe instead of wraith band

dagon
recipe changed

veil of discord
recipe changed

drum of endurance
recipe changed

rod of atos

ring of basilius
mana regeneration increased from 0.5 to 0.65

bloodstone
no longer has pocket deny
no longer reduces respawn times
now passively doubles your mana regeneration
starts with 12 charges, deaths remove 3 charges, kills provide 1 charge
each charge provides 0.25 mp and hp regen
can now be cast, transferring 60% of your current mana to health. cooldown: 250
regen is provided over 2 seconds.

aeon disk
health increased from 250 to 300
mana increased from 250 to 300
no longer provides passive status resistance
provides +50% status resistance during the 2.5s active buff duration

satanic
passively provides 30% status resistance
bonus damage reduced from 50 to 25

heart of tarrasque
now provides +50% health regen amplification
out-of-combat regen reduced from 7% to 5%
adjustment for the heal amp
hp bonus reduced from 500 to 400
now requires reaver, vitality booster, ring of tarrasque and 400 gold recipe

spirit vessel
no longer amplifies health regen nor provides current health percentage regen
enemy damage per second increased from 20 to 25
matches urn now. still deals current health as damage and negates regen

headdress
recipe reduced from 300 to 175

mekansm
recipe increased from 900 to 950
overall cost reduced by 75

arcane boots
mana restore increased from 135 to 160

guardian greaves
heal increased from 275 to 300
mana restore increased from 160 to 200

pipe of insight
now gives the +2 stats from its components
insight aura health regeneration increased from 2 to 3

skull basher
recipe cost reduced from 1000 to 900

butterfly
no longer has an active ability

crystalys
bonus damage increased from +30 to +38

desolator
armor reduction increased from 6 to 7

force staff
can now override slark's pounce

hand of midas
attack speed increased from 30 to 40

sentry ward
range increased from 850 to 1000

gem of true sight
grants 300 ground vision to the team that last held until it is picked up

morbid mask
no longer provides +10 damage
cost reduced from 1100 to 900

mask of madness
damage reduced from +20 to +10
see also
versions
patches
